## Web Developer | Software Engineer

# DANIEL JORDAN

8437 S. Toledo Ave. Tulsa, OK 74137 | (918) 814-4039 | djordan218@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/djordan218 | github.com/djordan218 | danielthedeveloper.com

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Certified Software Engineer with background in problem-solving experience in healthcare and diverse leadership and communicative skills in the military. I am highly driven and self-motivated to exceed expectations. Skilled in several web languages and frameworks including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Flask, Express, React, Node.js, and PostgreSQL. Experienced in front-end and back-end development. Very excited to be a part of your company and use my love for programming and skills in problem-solving to improve any project or product!

#### **SKILLS**

WEB DEVELOPMENT & SOFTWARE ENGINEERING: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Flask, Jinja, SQL, PostgreSQL, Node.js, Express.js, React, Redux, jQuery, Bootstrap, DOM Manipulation, Git, AJAX, Axios.

PROBLEM-SOLVING & SELF-DRIVE: Healthcare & military problem-solving experience with vast diagnoses with various plans of care, self-drive to accurately and efficiently improve patient outcomes as best as possible.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Springboard Software Engineering Program | SWE/Web Developer Training | July 2022 - February 2023 800+ hours of hands-on course material, with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of 4 in-depth portfolio projects. Mastered skills in front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms. Wrote and maintained code, developed unit integration tests, isolated and worked on bug fixes, and improved my ability to learn new languages and software technologies quickly.

- Green Thumb Web Application HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node.js, PostgreSQL, AWS
  A web application for managing a garden. A user creates a profile, can edit profile data, add
  crops to their garden from API, create crops to add to API, and edit/delete accordingly. Hosted
  through AWS using an S3 bucket, API Gateway, AWS Lambda, and RDS. Designed and consumed a
  REST API, using object oriented concepts, and executed relational database systems.
- Movie or Snoozie Web Application HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Flask, Python, AWS
   A movie search application that decides if a movie should be watched based on user data and preferences. A user sets their movie rating standards, as well as bedtime and then the app decides if the movie is good enough and that it will end before a user's bedtime. Hosted on AWS through EC2 instances.
- 395th Army Band iOS/Android Mobile App React, React Native, Expo
  A mobile app used for managing communication and information within the 395th Army Band.
  Soldiers are able to access common documents and schedules, get updated contact information, edit their own information, and admins can edit/delete/add FAQs, email rosters, and common contacts that are frequently needed by members of the unit.

Enhabit Home Health | Physical Therapist Assistant | December 2019 - Present Provided direct patient care to adult and geriatric individuals with diverse pathologies utilizing modalities, therapeutic exercise, and patient education. Communicated and assisted in complex problem solving that resulted in improved lives and quality of life of patients.

Carter Healthcare | Physical Therapist Assistant | August 2016 - December 2019
Provided direct patient care to adult and geriatric individuals with diverse pathologies utilizing modalities, therapeutic exercise, and patient education. Communicated and assisted in complex problem solving that resulted in improved lives and quality of life of patients.

United States Army Reserve | Secret Security Clearance | 42R Army Musician | March 2009 - Present Serving as senior leader of rank SFC/E-7, platoon sergeant, managing several subordinates within the platoon. Serve as Training & Operations NCOIC, managing Google Drive and creating documents to help ensure on-time training and data collection to send to higher command by designing and developing automation scripts and forms. Skills in leadership, timely communication, and interpersonal communication are used to manage subordinates and administrative duties in the unit.

#### **EDUCATION**

Springboard Software Engineering Program | SWE Certificate | August 2022 - Present Tulsa Community College | Associate of Applied Science | May 2013 - August 2016 University of Arkansas | Bachelor of Music Education | August 2008 - August 2011